Guide to the Jacob Gould Schurman papers, 1867-1942 [1986].
Schurman, Jacob Gould papers, 1867-1942 [1986].
- Series I. Correspondence, 1877-1942
  - Incoming Correspondence, 1879-1942 (Reel 2-7)
    - Wilson, Henry Lane; Slaton, John M.; Frank, Leo., May-June 1915 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Taft, William Howard; Pound, Cuthbert W.; Treman, Charles E.; Bossange, E. Raymond., July 1915 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Irish, W. M.; Simson, Louis A.; Nasmyth, George W. Cornell Day; World Peace Foundation., Aug. 1915 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Williams, E. L.; Saxe, Martin., Aug. 1915 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Irish, W. M.; Wakeley, Arthur C.; Thilly, Frank; Crist, Arthur H.; Wilson, Henry Lane; Hughes, Charles E.; Fetter, Frank A., Sept. 1915 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Wilson, Henry Lane; Borah, William E.; Scott, James Brown; Adamson, Ethel M.; Hammond, William A.; Betts, Charles H.; Elliott, John Lovejoy; Wilson, Henry Lane. Carnegie Endowment for International Peace; New York State Woman Suffrage Association., Oct.-Nov. 1915 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Shiraishi, J.; Stanton, Theodore; Day, James R.; Taft, William Howard; Schurman, Major. Tokyo Chamber of Commerce; Morse Hall., Dec. 1915 Mar. 1916 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Wilson, Henry Lane; Hilles, Charles D.; Howells, William Dean; Hughes, Charles E.; Taft, William Howard; Bois, Jules; Whitman, Charles S.; Putnam, G. H. Mexico., Apr.-June 1916 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Hughes, Charles E.; Putnam, G. H.; Wilson, Henry Lane; Holt, Hamilton., July-Oct. 1916 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Steinmetz, Charles P.; Adler, Felix., Nov. 1916 Feb. 1917 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Hiscock, Frank H.; Schurman, Major; Guanes, Luis., Mar.-May 1917 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Menocal, M. G. American Field Service in France; Relief Committee for Greeks of Asia Minor; Tinkham, Edward Isley;Barton, Colonel Frank A.; Hugo, Francis M.; Rammelkamp, Charles H.; Daniels, Josephine; Putnam, George Haven; Neilson, William Allen; Bettens, Edward D., June-Oct. 1917 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Bettens, Edward D.; House, E. M.; Wanamaker, John. Relief Committee for Greeks of Asia Minor; Hadley, Arthur Twining., Nov.-Dec. 1917 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - House, E. M.; Wilson, Woodrow; Schurman, Major; Guerlac, O. G.; Schwab, Charles M.; Taft, William Howard; Schiff, Jacob H.; Bliss, Cornelius N.; Lowell, Lawrence. American Red Cross., Jan.-Mar. 1918 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Branner, John C.; Hammond, William A.; Foraker, Joseph B.; Schiff, Jacob H.; Jusserand, Jean Jules; Yu, Chian Chang; Kipling, Rudyard; Parkin, George A.; Megata, Tanetari. University of California; Jacob H. Schiff Fund; Tsing Hua College, Peking; China., Mar.-Sept. 1918 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Beaverbrook, William Maxwell; Jones, Robert T.; Gazepis, George. University of Athens., Oct.-Dec. 1918 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Schiff, Jacob H.; Hughes, Charles E.; Higgins, Bertha D.; Clémenceau, Georges; Hays, William H.; Cornell, Caroline H.; Young, Allyn A. University of Basle., Jan.-Apr. 1919 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot; Van Dyke, Henry; Knickerbacker, John; Betts, Charles H. University of Paris., June-Dec. 1919 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Bryan, William J.; Wadsworth, James W. Hull, Charles H.; Adams, Joseph B.; Sampson, Martin; White, J. DuPratt; White, Horace; Trainor, John; Moody, Harriet; Burdick, Charles K. League of Nations., Jan.-Feb. 1920 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Smith, Alfred E.; Cornell, Charles Ezra; Comstock, John Henry; Blood, Charles H.; Titchener, E. M.; Treman, Robert H., Feb. 1920 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Gannett, Frank E.; Peer, Sherman; Westinghouse, H. H.; Strunk, William., Feb. 1920 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Burns, James; Love, H. H.; Fennell, Thomas F.; Scribner, Arthur H., Feb. 1920 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Gannett, Frank E.; Newman, Jared T.; Willcox, Bertram., Feb. 1920 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Hiscock, Frank H.; Jordan, David Starr; Knickerbacker, John; Russell, Charles M., Mar. 1920 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Willcox, Walter F., Mar. 1920 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Jones, Robert T.; Brown, Elon R.; Holme, E. H., Mar. 1920 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Associate Alumni of Cornell University., Apr.-May 1920 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Harding, Warren G.; Pound, Cuthbert W.; Kwei, Chi-ting. University of the Philippines., June 1920 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - White, H. S.; Putnam, Henry Sibley; Harding, Warren G.; Pound, Roscoe., July 1920 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Harding, Warren G. Republican National Committee; League of Nations., Aug.-Sept. 1920 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Harding, Warren G.; Hoover, Herbert; Wadsworth, James W., Oct.-Dec. 1920 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Harding, Warren G.; Dominick, D. C.; Brown, Arthur J.; Hughes, Charles E.; Moody, Harriet; Sze, Sao-Ke Alfred. China., Jan.-May 1921 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Sze, Sao-Ke Alfred; Walker, Guy M.; Brown, Arthur J.; Wadsworth, James W.; Holt, Hamilton; Thilly, Frank. China., May 1921 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Harding, Warren G.; Hughes, Charles E. China., June-Sept. 1921 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Harding, Warren G.; Lodge, Henry Cabot; Wadsworth, James W., Oct. 1921 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Feng, U. H.; Hughes, Charles E.; Harding, Warren G.; Chang, Tso-lin; Wood, Leonard; Buffington, Joseph. Philippines., Nov. 1921 Sept. 1922 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Fish, Hamilton; Buffington, Joseph; Wood, Leonard. China., Sept.-Nov. 1922 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Wu, C. C.; Meiklejohn, Alexander; Washington, Thomas; Wood, Leonard; Wilhelm, Richard., Feb.-Dec. 1923 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Yao, Tang Chi; Coolidge, Calvin; Wood, Leonard; Denton, Mary Florence. China., Feb.-Apr. 1924 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Wood, Leonard; Coolidge, Calvin; Jenkins, Douglas; Straight, Dorothy; Straight, Willard; McVay, Charles B.; de Fleuriau, A., May-Dec. 1924 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Hoffman, Alice; Coolidge, Calvin; Sokolsky, George E. China., Jan.-Feb. 1924 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Coolidge, Calvin. China., Mar. 1925 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - McVay, Charles B.; Washington, Thomas; Coolidge, Calvin., Mar. 1925 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Huston, J. C.; Feng, Yu-hsiang; Washington, Thomas; Webber, Leroy; Liebert, Arthur., Apr. 1925 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Washington, Thomas; Heinemann, Leopold; Schurman, George W.; Robbins, Warren D.; Hoetzsch, Otto; Connor, Elsa., Apr.-June 1925 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Thilly, Frank; Schurman, George W.; Hindenburg, Paul von; Liebert, Arthur; Connor, William D.; Bartholdy, A. Mendelssohn; Shotwell, James T.; Heinemann, Leopold. China; Carnegie Endowment for International Peace; Germany., July 1925 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Duisberg, Carl; Boyé, A.; Schiff, Mortimer L.; Kellogg, Frank B.; Marcosson, Isaac F.; Ostroumoff, Boris V.; Cunningham, Edwin S. Germany; China., Aug.-Sept. 1925 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Maltzan, Baron von; Marcosson, Isaac F.; Bueb, Julius; Duisberg, Carl; White, Horatio S.; Thilly, Frank; Connor, William D.; Ostroumoff, Boris V.; Bosch, C. Germany; China., Sept. 1925 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Schurman, George W.; Ostroumoff, Boris V.; Kellogg, Frank B.; Lee, Frederic E.; Hoover, Herbert., Oct. 1925 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Sokobin, Samuel; Muirhead, Lewis A.; Schurman, Anna Maria à; Ostroumoff, Boris V. China; American Committee on the Rights of Religious Minorities., Oct.-Nov. 1925 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Washburn, Albert H.; Castle, William R.; Hanson, G. C.; Ostroumoff, Boris V.; Stresemann, Gustav; Pao, Kwei-Ching. Locarno Treaty; Germany., Nov.-Dec. 1925 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Morrow, Dwight W.; Muirhead, Lewis A.; Seth Pringle-Pattison, Andrew; Liebert, Arthur; Thilly, Frank; Castle, William R.; Schurman, George W. Germany; Garantie und Kredit Bank fur den Osten., Jan.-Feb. 1926 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Thilly, Frank; Stresemann, Gustav; Liebert, Arthur; Smith, A. St. Clair; Seth Pringle-Pattison, Andrew; Kellogg, Frank B. Germany., Feb.-Apr. 1926 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Thilly, Frank; Liebert, Arthur; Kellogg, Frank B.; Thiersch, H.; Alexander, William J.; Klemperer, Herbert von; Schurman, Anna Maria à; Hilles, Charles D. Germany; Republican National Committee., Apr.-June 1926 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Weyer, S. Dunbar; Kellogg, Frank B.; Stoddard, Henry L.; Liebert, Arthur; Jones, Robert T.; Poole, H. C.; Medofsky, M.; Castle, William R., July-Sept. 1926 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Koch-Weser, Erich; Davis, J. K.; Deetjen, Werner; Butler, Nicholas Murray; Liebert, Arthur; Coolidge, Calvin. China; Carnegie Endowment for International Peace., Sept.-Dec. 1926 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Liebert, Arthur. Philippines; Germany., Jan.-Mar. 1927 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Kellogg, Frank B.; Hoops, Johannes. University of Heidelberg; Dawes Plan; Germany., Apr.-June 1927 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Kellogg, Frank B.; MacMurray, J. A.; Stresemann, Gustav; Hilles, Charles D.; Castle, William R. University of Heidelberg; Germany; Republican National Committee., June-Sept. 1927 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Hindenburg, Paul von; Koch-Weser, Erich; Schurman, Barbara Munro; Kellogg, Frank B.; Rockefeller, John D.; Stresemann, Gustav; Speyer, James; Stoehr, Max W.; Taft, Charles P.; Schiff, Mortimer L. University of Göttingen; University of Heidelberg., Oct.-Dec. 1927 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Gradenwitz, Otto; Speyer, James; Hoops, Johannes; Dibelius, Martin. University of Heidelberg., Jan. 1928 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Hoops, Johannes; Dietrich, Herman; Taft, Charles P.; Stresemann, Gustav; Rosenwald, Julius; Stoehr, Max W. University of Heidelberg., Jan. 1928 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Warburg, Paul M.; Scott, W. B.; Dibelius, Martin; Speyer, James; Preuss, Else; Hoops, Johannes; Biermann, Georg. University of Heidelberg., Feb. 1928 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Biermann, Georg; Nernst, W.; Eastman, George; Salin, Edgar; Willcox, Walter F.; Rosenhaim, Herman; Hoops, Johannes. University of Heidelberg; China., Mar. 1928 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Eastman, George; Hoops, Johannes; Dibelius, Martin. University of Heidelberg., Mar.-Apr. 1928 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Adickes, Erich; Willcox, Walter F.; Schirmer, H.; Eastman, George; Stoehr, Max W., Apr. 1928 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - König, Edm. von; Eastman, George; Vogel, Friedrich; Hoops, Johannes., May 1928 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Hoops, Johannes; Hammond, William A.; Andreas, W.; Perkins, Janet; Vogel, Friedrich; Hoops, Johannes; Winters, Carl; Stoehr, Max W.; Norton, W. J. University of Heidelberg., May 1928 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Hammond, William A.; Winters, Carl; König, Edm. von; Dibelius, Martin; Andreas, W.; Hoops, Johannes; Hoetzsch, Otto. University of Heidelberg., June 1928 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Hoetzsch, Otto; Norton, W. J.; Stoehr, Max W. University of Heidelberg., June 1928 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Winters, Carl; Rockefeller, John D.; Hughes, Charles E.; Hoover, Herbert; Hoops, Johannes; Speyer, James; Curtis, Charles. University of Heidelberg., June 1928 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Rosenwald, Julius; Dibelius, Martin; Rockefeller, John D.; Stoehr, Max W.; Hoops, Johannes., June 1928 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Warburg, Paul M.; Dibelius, Martin; White, Edward A.; Baker, George F.; Rockefeller, John D. University of Heidelberg., July 1928 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - König, Edm. von; Hoops, Johannes; Hoover, Herbert; Coolidge, Calvin; Nernst, W.; Atherton, Ray., Aug. 1928 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Kellogg, Frank B.; Warburg, Paul M.; Weber, Wilhelm., Sept. 1928 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Sachs, Samuel; Schniewind, Henry; Salin, Edgar; Brown, James; Woodin, William H. University of Heidelberg., Oct. 1928 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Smith, Lloyd H.; Oberlaender, Gustav; Forstmann, Julius; Bache, Jules S. University of Heidelberg., Oct. 1928 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Gramm, Hanns; Thun, Ferdinand; Janssen, Henry; Oberlaender, Gustav; Speyer, James. University of Heidelberg., Oct. 1928 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Woodin, William H. University of Heidelberg., Oct. 1928 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Rosenwald, Julius; Goldman, Henry; Stoehr, Max W.; Walker, Elisha. University of Heidelberg., Oct. 1928 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Taft, Charles P.; Schuster, Richard; Oberlaender, Gustav; Baker, George F.; Coolidge, Calvin. University of Heidelberg., Nov. 1928 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Rosenwald, Julius; Rockefeller, John D. University of Heidelberg., Nov. 1928 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Schniewind, Henry; Oberlaender, Gustav; Hoops, Johannes., Nov. 1928 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Stoehr, Max W.; Braman, S.; Heinsheimer, Karl; Reinhold, Peter. University of Heidelberg., Dec. 1928 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Eckener, Hugo; Heinsheimer, Karl. Carl Schurz Memorial Foundation; University of Heidelberg., Dec. 1928 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Hoops, Johannes. University of Heidelberg., Dec. 1928 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Heinsheimer, Karl. University of Heidelberg., Jan. 1929 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Rosenwald, Julius; Heinsheimer, Karl; Coolidge, Grace; Coolidge, Calvin. University of Heidelberg., Feb. 1929 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Heinsheimer, Karl; Merkenschlager, F.; Dibelius, Wilhelm; Thun, Ferdinand. Carl Schurz Memorial Foundation; University of Heidelberg., Mar. 1929 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Salomon-Calvi, Wilhelm; Loew, Oscar; Paulli, Eugen; Dibelius, Wilhelm; Stresemann, Gustav; Neuhaus, Fritz Berthold. University of Heidelberg., Apr. 1929 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - McHugh, James M.; Stresemann, Gustav; Case, Harry L.; Schurman, John; Dibelius, Martin; Thomsen, Hans; Hoops, Johannes. China; University of Heidelberg., May 1929 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Birthday greeting telegrams and letters., May 1929 (Box 5, Folder 4-8)
    - Dibelius, Martin., June 1929 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Koch-Weser, Erich; Bright, Edward; Hammond, William A.; Thilly, Frank; Walter, Ellery., July 1929 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Linthicum, J. Charles; Koch-Weser, Erich; Liebert, Arthur; McHugh, James M., Aug. 1929 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Gannett, Frank E.; Case, Harry L.; Schurman, George W.; Walter, Ellery; Grühl, Max., Sept. 1929 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Stresemann, Gustav; Walter, Ellery; Ebert, Louise; Bismarck, Princess; Dibelius, Martin; Case, Harry L.; Schurman, Robert; Haeberle, A. T., Oct. 1929 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Oncken, Herman; McHugh, James M.; van Loon, Hendrik Willem; Grühl, Max; Bernhard, Henry; Bauer, Heinrich., Nov. 1929 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Hoops, Johannes; Gutbier, L. W.; Fürstenberg, Hans., Dec. 1929 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Gutbier, L. W.; Curtius, Julius; Hoops, Johannes; Kuh, Frederick; Heineken, Ph. American Chamber of Commerce in Germany., Dec. 1929 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Gabler, Fritz; Kühenemann, Eugen; Petri, Walther; Hoetzsch, Otto; Heye, Wilhelm; Marx, Wilhelm., Dec. 1929 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Heye, Wilhelm., Dec. 1929 Jan. 1930 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Nernst, W.; Elster, Ernst; Emerson, Alfred; Hoops, Johannes; Erler, Fritz; Huddle, J. Klahr; Liebert, Arthur; Reimold, Emil., Jan. 1930 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Liebert, Arthur; Patton, K. S., Jan. 1930 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Leonard, Walter F.; Luther, Hans; Oncken, Herman; Koch-Weser, Erich., Jan. 1930 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Stock, Robert; Müller, Paul; Honold, F.; Centoz, Louis; Hindenburg, Paul von., Jan. 1930 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Kardorff, S. von; Goldschmidt, Jakob; Hoops, Johannes; Hindenburg, Paul von; Tschirch, Emil., Jan. 1930 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Lawrence, Richard W.; Hilles, Charles D.; Kehl, W.; Hughes, Charles E. National Republican Club; Republican National Committee., Feb. 1930 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Adenauer, Konrad; Pound, Cuthbert W.; Roosevelt, Franklin D.; Newman, Jared T.; Faust, A. B., Mar. 1930 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Langdon, Jervis; Strong, William Gillespie; Boochever, Louis C.; Flack, Harold; Stresemann, Gustav; Osmeña, Sergio. Philippines., Apr.-July 1930 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Bullock, Charles J.; Stresemann, Gustav; Tschirch, Emil., Aug.-Sept. 1930 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Scheidely, Joseph; Schurman, Barbara Munro; Curtius, A.; Washington, Thomas; Burr, George Lincoln; Bancroft, Wilder; Hughes, Charles E.; Farrand, Livingston; Cornell, Caroline H., Oct.-Nov. 1930 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Schurman, Barbara Munro; Stresemann, Kaete; Jones, Robert T.; Hammond, William A.; Simon, H. F.; Kuh, Frederick; Mann, A. R., Nov. 1930 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Schurman, Barbara Munro; Schurman, Minnie; Cornell, Mary E.; Hoops, Johannes; Hindenburg, Paul von., Nov. 1930 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Dibelius, Martin; Burdick, Charles K.; Brown, Arthur J.; Heineken, Ph.; Carman, Alice B.; Elster, Erich; Willcox, Bertram; Hoy, David F., Nov. 1930 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Connor, William D.; Walker, James J.; Flack, Harold; Hindenburg, Paul von., Nov. 1930 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Ferguson, John C.; Seth Pringle-Pattison, Andrew; Patterson, Woodford; Stresemann, Gustav., Nov. 1930 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Bruening, Heinrich; Hilles, Charles D., Nov. 1930 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Taylor, Myron C.; Rutherford, Daisy; White, Horatio S.; Andreas, W., Dec. 1930 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Curtius, Julius., 1930 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Kirk, Clara; Seth Pringle-Pattison, Andrew; Brown, Arthur J.; Fuentes, Ismail G.; Koch-Weser, Irma; Schurman, M. F., Jan.-June 1931 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Rutherford, Daisy; Hadaway, William S.; Léon, Maurice. Schurman family genealogy., Aug.-Oct. 1931 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Hadaway, William S.; Leon, Maurice. Schurman family genealogy., Nov.-Dec. 1931 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Stimson, Henry L.; McHugh, James M.; Pound, Cuthbert W., Jan.-Mar. 1932 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Speyer, James; Osmeña, Sergio. Philippines., June-Oct. 1932 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Osmeña, Sergio; Capper, J. B.; Schurman, M. F. Philippines., Nov.-Dec. 1932 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Osmeña, Sergio; Sotto, Vincente; Quezon, Manuel L.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. Philippines; Philippine Civic Union., Jan.-Nov. 1933 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Hull, Cordell; Wallace, Tom. Birthday felicitations., Mar.-May 1934 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - White, J. DuPratt., May 1934 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Thomas, Wilbur K.; Dodd, William E.; Petro, W.; Alexander, William J., July 1934Sept. 1935 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Rockefeller, John D.; Burke, Edward R.; Hull, Cordell., Aug. 1936 Sept. 1937 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Gannett, Frank E.; Hammond, William A.; Ridder, Victor F.; Alexander, William J., Jan.-Nov. 1938 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Tydings, Millard E.; Osmeña, Sergio., May-Aug. 1939 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Robinson, Thomas L.; Thomas, Wilbur K.; Thun, Ferdinand; Burke, Edward R.; Gannett, Frank E. Carl Schurz Memorial Foundation., Feb.-Oct. 1940 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Letter from Schurman., Apr. 1941 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Kinne, Birge W. Letters of condolence on the death of Jacob Gould Schurman to Jacob Gould Schurman, Jr., Aug. 1942 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Schurman, M. F.; Lefkowitz, Louis J. Letters of condolence on the death of Jacob Gould Schurman to Jacob Gould Schurman, Jr., Aug. 1942 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Farley, James A. Letters of condolence on the death of Jacob Gould Schurman to Jacob Gould Schurman, Jr., Aug. 1942 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Schurman, M. F. Letters of condolence on the death of Jacob Gould Schurman to Jacob Gould Schurman, Jr., Aug. 1942 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Rockefeller, John D.; LeBoeuf, Randall J. Letters of condolence on the death of Jacob Gould Schurman to Jacob Gould Schurman, Jr., Aug. 1942 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Letters of condolence on the death of Jacob Gould Schurman to Jacob Gould Schurman, Jr., Aug. 1942 (Box 6, Folder 23-24)
    - Lehman, Herbert H.; Hughes, Charles E.; La Guardia, F. H.; Gannett, Frank E. Telegrams of condolence on the death of Jacob Gould Schurman to Jacob Gould Schurman, Jr., Aug. 1942 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Taylor, Myron C.; Wagner, Robert F.; Shih, Hu. Telegrams of condolence on the death of Jacob Gould Schurman to Jacob Gould Schurman, Jr., Aug. 1942 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Speyer, James; Wilson, Tom; Garland, Hamlin; James, William; Stanton, Elizabeth Cady; Stresemann, Kaete; Stresemann, Gustav; Smith, Goldwin; Mitchell, P. Chalmers. (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Clément, M.; Chatfield-Taylor, H. C.; Bigelow, Poultney; Rhys, John; Robbins, Reginald C.; Nixon, S. F.; Stresemann, Kaete; Osmeña, Sergio; Hoffman, Alice., n.d. (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence. (Box 6, Folder 29-31)
  - Letterbooks (Outgoing Correspondence), 1889-1921 (Reel 8-47)
    An extensive index to the letterbooks is available here. 9 MB PDF file.
    The letterbook copy impressions of letters written by Schurman as President of Cornell University profile both his personal character and formal manner in the execution of his administrative duties. A few letters of Charles Kendall Adams commence the letterbooks, and Acting Presidents are the signatories of several letters, notably T. F. Crane 1912 and 1913 when Schurman was serving as Ambassador to Greece, and Acting President Albert W. Smith in 1920 and 1921. Volumes 1-50 are letters signed by President Schurman; volumes 51-80 are letters signed by President Schurman's Secretary on behalf of the Office of the President.
    In addition to the routine administrative subjects in the correspondence that devolved typically from the Office of the President of Cornell, topics include the 1903 typhoid epidemic in Ithaca, the establishment of the Carnegie Fund, the Leo Frank case, the Chi Psi fire, the construction of several new campus buildings, co-education and women students, African-American students on campus, and relations with Ithaca, New York. Other topics and concerns in the letterbooks include the president's relations with faculty, college benefactors, and presidents of other universities; also, fraternities and campus housing, foreign students, religious education, and Sage Chapel preachers. President Schurman made several appearances before alumni groups throughout the nation, and correspondence to this effect is plentiful. Cornell's relations with other universities, other associations of American universities, and educational societies are mentioned frequently. The element of publicity is suggested by Schurman's many letters to newspapers, magazines, and publishers. The university's role in World War I is shown as the president assists in the mobilization of resources and facilitates the university's preparation of its students to become soldiers; letters to the United States War Department are numerous. The development of the New York State College of Agriculture and the New York State Veterinary College at Cornell is referred to in many letters, as well as a proposed School of Forestry. Schurman corresponded frequently with Andrew Carnegie, and with officials of the Carnegie Foundation and the Carnegie Corporation. He also wrote many letters to immediate family members of Ezra Cornell.
    Principal recipients of letters include Lyman Abbott, Liberty Hyde Bailey, Frank Barton, C. E. Bennett, Charles H. Blood, George Boldt, G. P. Bristol, J. E. Creighton, L. M. Dennis, W. A. Hammond, Frank H. Hiscock, Charles Evans Hughes, C. H. Hull, David Starr Jordan, A. T. Kerr, D. S. Kimball, Albert R. Mann, Veranus A. Moore, Jared T. Newman, Henry S. Pritchett, C. W. Pound, W. M. Polk, Robert F. Plummer, Theodore Roosevelt, H. W. Sackett, M. W. Sampson, A. W. Smith, Goldwin Smith, William Howard Taft, Frank Thilly, Mynderse Van Cleef, Andrew Dickson White, J. DuPratt White, W. F. Willcox, and C. V. P. "Tar" Young. In addition to these principal recipients, many additional names are listed in the index, including such important Cornell personalities as Willard Straight, E. B. Titchener, and Martha Van Rensselaer.
    - Feb. 11, 1889 to Nov. 4, 1893 (Volume 1, Reel 8)
    - Nov. 6, 1893 to Nov. 19, 1984 (Volume 2, Reel 8)
    - Nov. 20, 1894 to Oct. 17, 1895 (Volume 3, Reel 9)
    - Oct. 16, 1895 to Oct. 29, 1896 (Volume 4, Reel 9)
    - Nov. 21, 1896 to Jan. 10, 1898 (Volume 5, Reel 10)
    - Jan. 10, 1898 to Jan. 6 1899 (Volume 6, Reel 10)
    - Jan. 6, 1899 to Feb. 14, 1900 (Volume 7, Reel 11)